An outlier is a data point that is far away from the rest of the data.
离群值是指和其他数据相距很远的数据点
Outliers can appear in your data for similar reasons to missing data.
数据集中出现离群值的原因和出现缺失值类似
An outlier could be due to a data entry error or a processing mistake,
离群值可能是因为数据录入错误或者处理时的错误
or an outlier might be legitimate data because, in any situation,
或者离群值可能就是合法的 因为在任何情况下
there's always some probability of obtaining an extreme value.
总有可能得到极端值
The questions to ask yourself are;
需要反思的问题有
how do you find outliers,
如何找到离群值
and then once you found them,
以及一旦你找到了
what do you do with them?
你应该如何处理它们
First, I'll introduce a few ways for detecting
首先 你会介绍几种检测离群值的方法
outliers and then talk about what to do with outliers.
然后探讨如果处理离群值
When working in one or two dimensions,
当处理一或二维数据时
you can use data visualizations to spot outliers.
你可以使用数据可视化的方法来检测离群值
In the case of one dimensional data,
对于一维数据
you can plot the data along a number line.
你可以在数轴上标出所有数据
A data point that falls far to the left or far to
一个落在数轴上特别靠左或者靠右的数据点
the right of most of the data could be considered an outlier.
会被认为是离群值
You can also spot outliers using two dimensional plots.
你还可以使用二维图像来检测离群值
In this plot, it's clear that one point is far away from the other data points.
在这幅图像中 显然有一个点离其他点都很远
There are also statistical methods for finding outliers,
检测离群值还有一些统计学的方法
and I'll give you some practice in the coding exercises.
这里有一些代码练习
These include using z-scores from a normal distribution or the two-key method.
包括使用正态分布产生的 z 分数或者Tukey检测法
Both of these methods use basic statistics like means,
这两种方法都使用了基本的统计量 如平均数
standard deviations, or quantiles to
标准差或者分位数
identify outliers that are far away from most of the data.
来检测距离大多数数据点很远的离群值
So far, we've talked about finding outliers in one or two dimensions.
目前为止 我们讨论了如何检测一维或二维的离群值
How do you find outliers in three or more dimensions?
如何检测三维甚至更高维度的离群值
You could, for example,
你可以 比如
use machine learning techniques like PCA to reduce the data to one or two dimensions.
使用机器学习算法 如PCA 将数据维度降到一维或者二维
Then you could use the graphical or statistical methods already discussed.
然后再使用上述的图像或者统计的方法
Another example would be to use a clustering method.
另一个例子是使用聚类算法
In this case, you would first calculate
这种情况下 你要先计算
the cluster centroids and then you would measure
聚类的中心 然后衡量
the distance between each centroid and each point.
每个数据点到中心的距离
A large distance might indicate an outlier.
距离大意味着是离群值
Scikit-learn also includes various outlier detection algorithms,
scikit-learn 同样包含很多离群值检测算法
and I'll provide a link below.
下面是一些链接
Next, you'll get some practice identifying outliers.
接下来 你将练习如何找到离群值